A Guide to the 8th Evacuation Hospital 1941-2011
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- LETTER FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO RANDOLPH PERRY 1969 April 171, Carbon copy TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 03-052)
- LETTER FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO REFERENCE DIVISION OF ALDERMAN LIBRARY, UVA RE: REQUEST FOR INFORMATION ON "AXIS SALLY" 1970 February 19, Carbon copy TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 03-053)
- LETTER FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO VICTOR REYNOLDS RE: REJECTION OF 8TH EVAC. HISTORY MS. BY UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA PRESS WITH ATTACHED NOTE, PROBABLY FROM STAIGE D. BLACKFORD 1969 May 16, Carbon copy TL and Note, typed, 2 pp. (Box-folder 03-054)
- LETTER FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO HERBERT SILVETTE 1969 May and August, Carbon copy TL 3 pp. (Box-folder 03-055)
- LETTER FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO MRS. EDWARD THROOP 1961 January 11, Carbon copy TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 03-056)
- LETTERS FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO FORMER MEMBERS OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL REQUESTING INFORMATION FOR THE HISTORY OF 8TH EVAC 1968 January-May, Carbon copy TL 41 pp. (Box-folder 03-057)
- LETTERS FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL TO FORMER MEMBERS OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL REQUESTING INFORMATION FOR THE HISTORY OF 8TH EVAC 1968 June-1970 February, Carbon copy TL 48 pp. (Box-folder 03-058)
- LETTERS FROM FORMER MEMBERS OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: RESPONSES TO REQUEST FOR INFORMATION FOR 8TH EVAC. HISTORY 1968 January-1969 Nov., TLS, ALS, AL, 58 pp. (Box-folder 03-059)
- MISCELLANEOUS LETTERS FROM BYRD STUART LEAVELL REQUESTING INFORMATION FOR THE HISTORY OF 8TH EVAC 1961-1969, TL 4 pp. (Box-folder 03-060)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: PERMISSION TO USE AND QUOTE MATERIAL IN MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1955-1969, TLS, TL 20 pp. (Box-folder 03-061)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: PERMISSION TO USE MATERIAL IN MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1969 February-April, TLS, TL 38 pp. (Box-folder 03-062)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF BYRD STUART LEAVELL AND CHARLES E. MORAN RE: POSSIBILITY OF PUBLISHING HISTORY OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL BY UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA PRESS 1960 January, TLS and Carbon copy TL 2 pp. (Box-folder 03-063)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: POSSIBILITY OF PUBLISHING MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE BY W. B. SAUNDERS CO., THE MICHIE COMPANY, AND PENGUIN BOOKS, INC. 1969 February-March, TLS and Carbon copy TL 4 pp. (Box-folder 03-064)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: POSSIBILITY OF PUBLISHING MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE BY HARCOURT, BRACE AND WORLD, INC., UNIVERSITY PRESS OF VIRGINIA, UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE PRESS, AND THE MICHIE COMPANY 1969 April-May, TLS and Carbon copy TL 5 pp. (Box-folder 03-065)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE OF HERBERT SILVETTE, SHERMAN P. CARTER, LOUIS T. IGLEHART, AND BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: POSSIBILITY OF PUBLISHING MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE BY UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE PRESS 1969 May-July, August, TLS and Carbon copy TL 12 pp. (Box-folder 03-066)
- CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN BYRD STUART LEAVELL AND AUGUST DIETZ RE: PRODUCTION, COSTS, AND DISTRIBUTION OF MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE BY DIETZ PRESS 1969-1972, TLS, TL 65 pp. (Box-folder 03-067)
- CORRESPONDENCE BETWEEN BYRD STUART LEAVELL AND VIRGINIA THATCHER RE: THATCHER'S PROOFREADING OF MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE; AND LETTER FROM WALKER COWEN OF THE UNIVERSITY PRESS OF VIRGINIA TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1969 November 24-1970 Jun, TLS, AL and Carbon copy TL 31 pp. (Box-folder 03-068)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1969-1970, ALS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 03-069)
- LETTER FROM BRIG. GEN. JOSEPH I. MARTIN TO STAIGE D. BLACKFORD 1949 January 5, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-001)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1970 August and July, TLS, ALS, TL, 12 pp. (Box-folder 04-002)
- CORRESPONDENCE RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1970 September, TLS, ALS, TL, 27 pp. (Box-folder 04-003)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1970 October, TLS, ALS, TL, 25 pp. (Box-folder 04-004)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1970 November, TLS, ALS, TL, 14 pp. (Box-folder 04-005)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1970 December-1971 Feb., TLS, ALS, TL, 22 pp. (Box-folder 04-006)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: READERS' RESPONSES TO MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1971 March-1972 March, TLS, ALS, TL, 20 pp. (Box-folder 04-007)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL CORRESPONDENCE RE: ADVERTISING SPACE FOR MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1971 January, TLS, ALS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 04-008)
  AMERICAN LEGION MAGAZINE, ARMY DIGEST, ARMY TIMES
- CORRESPONDENCE OF BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1968-1969, TLS, TL, ALS 5 pp. (Box-folder 04-009)
- LETTER FROM MRS. BYRD S. LEAVELL TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL N.D., ALS 4 pp. (Box-folder 04-010)
- LETTER FROM LUTIE CLEMSON LEAVELL TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1971 March 24, ALS 2 pp. (Box-folder 04-011)
- LETTER FROM MRS. BYRD S. LEAVELL TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1945 September 24, ALS 3 pp. (Box-folder 04-012)
- LETTER FROM J. RICHMOND LOW TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1968 February 20, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-013)
- LETTER FROM DONALD F. MARSHALL RE: MARSHALL'S RECOLLECTIONS OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY 1968 August 15, TLS 3 pp. (Box-folder 04-014)
- LETTER FROM BRIG. GEN. JOSEPH I. MARTIN TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL REUNION 1950 August 17, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-015)
- RECOLLECTIONS OF JOHN R. MORIS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: THE SHOCK TENT OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1968, ALS 2 pp. (Box-folder 04-016)
- LETTER FROM RANDOLPH H. PERRY TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1969 April 21, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-017)
- LETTER FROM HERBERT SILVETTE TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: SILVETTE'S COMMENTS ON LEAVELL'S 1ST DRAFT OF MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1969 April 17, TLS with autograph corrections 4 pp. (Box-folder 04-018)
- LETTER FROM HERBERT M. SMITH TO STAIGE D. BLACKFORD 1945 November 4, ALS 4 pp. (Box-folder 04-019)
- LETTER FROM HERBERT M. SMITH TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: USE OF ANESTHESIA IN 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1968 February 13, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-020)
- LETTER FROM JOHN D. SQUIER TO STAIGE D. BLACKFORD RE: REQUEST FOR BLACKFORD'S AID TO QUALIFY FOR A PURPLE HEART 1945 November, TLS, AN and Carbon copy, TL 3 pp. (Box-folder 04-021)
- LETTER FROM MAJOR GENERAL M. C. STAYER TO COL. LEWIS W. KIRKMAN RE: KIRKMAN'S HISTORY OF THE 8TH EVACUATION HOSPITAL 1945 March 26, Mimeograph TL 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-022)
- LETTER FROM MARY STEVENS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: REVIEW OF MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE 1970 August 20, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-023)
- LETTER FROM W. G. SUHLING, JR. TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: SUHLING'S RECOLLECTIONS OF THE 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1962 October 17, TLS 5 pp. (Box-folder 04-024)
- LETTER FROM W. G. SUHLING, JR. TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1969 October 1, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-025)
- LETTER FROM FRANCES THOMAS TO STAIGE D. BLACKFORD 1946 January, ALS 2 PP. (Box-folder 04-026)
- LETTER FROM FRANCES THOMAS TO STAIGE D. BLACKFORD N.D., ALS 2 pp. (Box-folder 04-027)
- LETTER FROM SHARON VANDERCOOK TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: ANSWER TO LEAVELL'S REQUEST FOR INFORMATION ON "AXIS SALLY" 1970 March 3, TLS plus Xerox of magazine article 3 pp. (Box-folder 04-028)
- LETTER FROM JOHN PAUL WINTHROP TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: THE DENTAL DEPARTMENT OF THE 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1964 April, TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-029)
- LETTER FROM ALBERT VANN ZALIS RE: OFFICERS', ENLISTED MEN'S AND PATIENT MESSES IN 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1968 June 17, TLS 2 pp. (Box-folder 04-030)
- LIST OF U.S. ARMY OFFICERS AND THEIR ASSIGNMENTS ADDRESSED TO WILLIAM P. SNAVELY 1942 August, Pamphlet 49 pp. (Box-folder 04-031)
- MEDICAL REPORTS-DIAGNOSIS AND POST-MORTEM OF PRIVATE MARTIN, PATIENT IN 8TH EVA. HOSPITAL IN ITALY 1942 December, AMsS 2 pp. and AMs 3 pp. (Box-folder 04-032)
- PASSES, TELEGRAMS, ORDERS, LISTS OF PERSONNEL FROM 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS OF WILLIAM P. SNAVELY 1942-1943, Mimeograph and Carbon copy TMs, AMs 15 pp. (Box-folder 04-033)
- SPECIAL ORDERS, CERTIFICATES, LETTER ORDERS, COURT MARTIAL, ETC. RE: 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY 1944 March-1945 November, Mimeograph TMs, AMs 27 pp. (Box-folder 04-034)
- RECEIPTS, INVENTORIES, CERTIFICATES, SPECIAL ORDERS, RE: 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL, ESP. MESS SECTION AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS OF WILLIAM P. SNAVELY 1944 March-1945 June, TMS, AMS and Carbon copy TMS 49 pp. (Box-folder 04-035)
- RECOMMENDATIONS FOR PROMOTION OF WILLIAM P. SNAVELY, FIFTH ARMY CITATION, AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS OF WILLIAM P. SNAVELY 1944 March-1945 November, Mimeograph TMs, TMsS 14 pp. (Box-folder 04-036)
- SHIPPING TICKETS, TALLY SHEETS, RECEIPTS, FROM 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1943-1944, Receipts 66 pp. (Box-folder 04-037)
- SPECIAL ORDERS, HOSPITAL ORDERS, MEMOS, SHIPPING TICKETS, REPORTS, ETC. FROM 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS OF WILLIAM P. SNAVELY 1945, Mimeograph TMS, Carbon copy TMs 215 pp. (Box-folder 04-038)
- TRAVEL ORDERS 1945 September 26, Mimeograph TMs 15 pp. 15 copies (Box-folder 04-039)
- 5TH ARMY CITATION FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL FROM MARK W. CLARK 1945, Doc. 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-040)
- 8TH EVAC. CITATION FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE UNIT PLAQUE 1945, Doc. 1 pg. (Box-folder 04-041)
- PENETRATING WOUNDS OF THE BRAIN, MANAGEMENT IN AN EVACUATION HOSPITAL-ARTICLE BY MAJ. EDWIN W. SHEARBURN AND CAPT. EDWIN H. MULFORD 1945, Xerox article 7 pp. (Box-folder 04-042)
- DESCRIPTION OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL DENTAL DEPARTMENT BY JOHN PAUL WINTHROP 1964, TMs and Carbon copy TMs 6 pp. (Box-folder 04-043)
- 8TH EVAC. CITATION FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE UNIT PLAQUE 1945, TD (Box-folder 04-045)
- 8TH EVAC. COMMENDATION LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT, UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA FROM GEN. JOSEPH T. MCNARNEY 1945 October 16, TD (Box-folder 04-046)
- NOTES ON CORRECTIONS AND ADDITIONS IN THE 1ST DRAFT OF MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE N.D., AMs 12 pp. (Box-folder 05-001)
- SPECIAL ORDERS, WEEKLY REPORTS, HOSPITAL ORDERS FROM 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL RE: MESS SECTION AND MESS OFFICER WILLIAM P. SNAVELY 1943-45, TMs and Carbon copy TMs 60 pp. (Box-folder 05-002)
- STATISTICAL REPORT, ITALY, HEADQUARTERS 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL, OFFICE OF THE REGISTRAR 1943 Dec. 19-1944 Dec. 31, Carbon copy TMs 35 pp., charts, etc. (Box-folder 05-003)
  INCLUDES A SHEET WITH THE LAST NAMES OF 72 MEN WHO WERE EVIDENTLY PATIENTS AT THE 8TH EVAC. MANY NAMES CORRESPOND WITH THOSE IN RUTH BEERY'S NOTEBOOK OF THE MEN WHO DIED AT THE 8TH EVAC. THE NAMES ARE LISTED ALPHABETICALLY BUT ONLY GO PARTWAY THROUGH THE LETTER H. THE STATISTICAL REPORT GIVES INFO ON ADMISSIONS DIAGNOSES, FRACTURES, CAUSATIVE AGENTS OF WOUNDED PATIENTS, DEATHS, AND VARIOUS CLINICS.
- LIST OF SUGGESTIONS MADE BY W. G. SUHLING TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: CORRECTIONS AND ADDITIONS FOR THE DRAFT OF MUD, MOUNTAINS, AND MEDICINE N.D., TMs with Autograph corrections (Box-folder 05-004)
- NOTES FROM W. G. SUHLING TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL RE: 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL N.D., TMs 3pp. (Box-folder 05-005)
- A FORMER 8TH EVAC. NURSE RE: LIVING CONDITIONS OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL NURSES, 1943-44 N.D., TL and AN 4 pp. (Box-folder 05-006)
- LETTER FROM CHARLES J. SIMPSON TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL 1968 May 3, TLS 2pp. (Box-folder 05-007)
- HISTORY OF THE DEPARTMENT OF RADIOLOGY OF THE EIGHTH EVACUATION HOSPITAL OF THE ARMY OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA IN WORLD WAR II BY JOHN R. MAPP 1968 January 29, TMsS 4 pp. (Box-folder 05-008)
- DIRECTORY OF PERSONNEL OF THE 8TH EVACUATION HOSPITAL [c.1945], Pamphlet 20 pp. copy 1 (Box-folder 05-009)
- PRESENT NEWS OF THE OFFICERS, A NEWSLETTER FOR FORMER MEMBERS OF THE 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL N.D., Mimeograph TMs 12 pp. copy 1 (Box-folder 05-010)
- PRESENT NEWS OF THE OFFICERS, A NEWSLETTER FOR FORMER MEMBERS OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL N.D., Mimeograph TMs 12 pp. ea., copy 2,3,4 (Box-folder 05-011)
- 8TH EVAC. XMAS LETTER, 1947 RE: NEWS OF FORMER 8TH EVAC. MEMBERS AND NEW ADDRESSES 1947 December, Mimeograph TMs 16 pp. copy 1, Mimeograph TMs 15 pp. copy 2 (Box-folder 05-012)
- PRESENT NEWS OF OFFICERS, A NEWSLETTER, INCLUDES POEM TITLED 8TH EVAC. EPIC BY E. G. LAIRD [1948], Mimeograph TMs 20 pp. copy 1 (Box-folder 05-013)
- PRESENT NEWS OF THE OFFICERS FROM 8TH EVAC. XMAS LETTER, 1947 1947 December, Mimeograph TMs 8 pp. (Box-folder 05-014)
- PRESENT NEWS OF OFFICERS, A NEWSLETTER, INCLUDES 2 COPIES OF POEM TITLED 8TH EVAC. EPIC BY E. G. LAIRD [1948], Mimeograph TMs 22 pp. copy 2 (Box-folder 05-015)
- DIRECTORY OF PERSONNEL OF THE 8TH EVACUATION HOSPITAL [1945], Pamphlet 20 pp. copy 2 (Box-folder 05-016)
- GENERAL ORDERS, NUMBER 113, AWARDS OF MERITORIOUS SERVICE UNIT PLAQUE. FROM HEADQUARTERS FIFTH ARMY, BY COMMAND OF LT. GENERAL TRUSCOTT 1945 September 10, Doc. 1 p. (Box-folder 05-017)
- RE: WAR IN ITALY, GENERAL WAR NEWS AND A FEW ITEMS ON 8TH EVAC. UNIT MEMBERS 1942-1945, Xerox Newspaper clippings 32 pp. (Box-folder 05-018)
  ELIZABETH ENGLEMAN, CATO DRASH, STAIGE D. BLACKORD
- LIST OF SOME FORMER MEMBERS OF THE 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL WITH ADDRESSES 1968-1969, Carbon copy and original TMs etc. (Box-folder 05-019)
- POEM THE EXPENDABLES WITH NOTE TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL N.D., TMs with AN 3 pp. (Box-folder 05-020)
- A SHORT HISTORY OF THE GRACE LINE, FROM FREDERIC P. SANDS, DIRECTOR, PUBLIC RELATIONS GRACE LINE 1958, Carbon copy TMs 20 pp. (Box-folder 05-021)
- SALE NEGOTIATED FOR GRACE LINE'S FORMER PASSENGER SHIP, THE SANTA PAULA, GRACE LINE NEWS, P. 30 1961 March 27, Newsletter 1 pg. (Box-folder 05-022)
- CALENDARS WITH PHOTO OF 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN PIETRAMALA, ITALY, CHRISTMAS 1944 1948-1949, Calendars, 2 (Box-folder 05-023)
- ARMED FORCES JOURNAL 1970 December 21, Magazine 50 pp. (Box-folder 05-024)
- LIST OF SOME ADDRESSES OF FORMER 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL MEMBERS 1970, AMs 3pp. (Box-folder 05-025)
- LETTERS TO BYRD STUART LEAVELL FROM BETTY AND ED KROOP, JOHN DEMPSEY AND GILBERT SULLIVAN N.D., 1961, 1969, 2 ANS, TLS (Box-folder 05-026)
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY, U.S. ARMY PHOTOS 1943-45, PHOTOS 15-B&W 5X7, 1-B&W 4X5, 2-B&W 8X10 (Box-folder 05-027)
  8th Evac. Hospital in Anfa Hill, Casablanca, and Italy
- 8TH EVAC. VIGNETTE, STAIGE D. BLACKFORD MEMORIAL LECTURE, CORRESPONDENCE TO BLACKFORD FROM FLOYD BRUNING, HOWARD HOLT AND [JOHN PAUL] WINTHROP N.D., 1945, 2 TD, 2 TL, 1 ANS (Box-folder 05-028)
- 8TH EVAC. IN CASABLANCA, AFRICA, PHOTOS TAKEN BY JOSEPH P. WINTHROP N.D. [1942-43?], PHOTOS 25-B&W 3.25X2.75 (Box-folder 05-029)
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA AND ITALY, PICTURES TAKEN BY JOSEPH P. WINTHROP 1943-45, PHOTOS 24-B&W 3.5X2.5 (Box-folder 05-030)
  8th Evac. in Casablanca, Italian Consulate in Casablanca and Pietramala, Spring, 1945
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL 1943-45, PHOTOS 3-B&W 4X5, 2-B&W 3.25X4.5, 3-B&W 2.75X4.5 (Box-folder 05-031)
  8th Evac. in Pietremala, and Teano; Mud, Operating Tent, X-Ray Area
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY, U. S. ARMY PHOTOGRAPHS SOME CLASSIFIED SECRET 1943-1945, PHOTOS 19 B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 05-032)
  8th Evac. in Pietramala; Dispensary, Operating Tent, X-Ray Dark Room, Mess Tent, Ward, Latrines, Operating Theaters, Tent Construction
- 25H EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA AND ITALY 1942-1945, PHOTOS 1-B&W 2.5X4.25, 2-B&W 3X4.5, 2-B&W 3.5X5, ETC. (Box-folder 05-033)
  8th Evac. in Casablanca, Italian Consulate in Casablanca, and Ravello; Purple Heart Ceremony; Tents; Vehicles
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY, U.S. ARMY PHOTOS, SOME CLASSIFED SECRET 1943-1945, PHOTOS 17-B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 05-034)
  8th Evac. in Pietramala, Teano, and Montecatini Area; Mess Tent, Shock Tent, Water Truck and Tank, Blood Bank, Utility Tent, Operating Room, X-Ray Department, Ambulance Turnabout, Lt. Gen. Mark Clark, Immunization Shots
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA AND MISCELLANEOUS PHOTOS N.D., PHOTOS 178 B&W (Box-folder 05-035)
  Casablanca, and Marrakesh; Rocks, Allied Parade, Set-Up at Anfa, Purple Heart Ceremony
- 8TH EVAC. UNIT IN ITALY, SEVERAL U.S. ARMY PHOTOS 1943-1945, PHOTOS 6-B&W 8X10 (Box-folder 05-036)
  Pietramala seen from Mt. Beni, Ambulances, Major John O. Mcneel, M. C., Registrar, 8th Evac. Hospital with Secretary of War Stimson
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY, U.S. ARMY PHOTOGRAPHS, SOME CLASSIFED SECRET 1943-1945, PHOTOS 14-B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 05-037)
  8th Evac. in Pietramala, and Teano; Snow, Wood Cutting, Mess Tent, Operating Theater, Wards, Aid Station
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN ITALY, U.S. ARMY PHOTOGRAPHS, SOME CLASSIFIED SECRET 1943-1945, PHOTOS 19-B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 05-038)
  8th Evac. in Capua Area, and Teano Area; Wood Cutting, Water Supply, Hospital Lab, X-Ray Tent, Operating Room, Utilities Tent, Winterization, Ward Building
- DONALD F. MARSHALL PRESENTED AWARD BY KIWANIS CLUB OF PORTLAND, MAINE 1975, Pamph (Box-folder 05-039)
- FIFTH ARMY ASSOCIATION MEMBER CARD OF LEWIS W. KIRKMAN 1944 December 15, TDS (Box-folder 05-040)
- DESCRIPTION OF PICTURES TAKEN BY VAN HANEY IN ITALY IN 1944-45 1944-45, DESCRIPTION OF PHOTOS TMS 15 PP 2 COPIES (Box-folder 06-001)
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 1-20 1944 FEBRUARY-APRIL, PHOTOS 14-B&W 2.75X4.5 (Box-folder 06-002)
  8th Evac. in Teano, and Carinola; USO Show, Various Individuals
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 21-40 1944 FEBRUARY-APRIL, PHOTOS 21-B&W 2.75X4.5 (Box-folder 06-003)
  8th Evac. in Caserta, Carinola, Teano, Riardo
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 41-60 1944 FEBRUARY-JUNE, PHOTOS 20-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-004)
  8th Evac. in Teano, Santa Maria, Cellole, Beach below Minturno; Stretching Tent, German prisoner patient, Marlene Dietrich Show
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 61-80 1944 JUNE, PHOTOS 29-B&W 2.7 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-005)
  June 1944 - Rome, Grosseto, Cisterna, Le Ferriere
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 81-100 1944 JUNE-JULY, PHOTOS 32-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-006)
  June 1944 - Cisterna, Le Ferriere, Rome, Cecina
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 101-120 1944 JULY-SEPTEMBER, PHOTOS 30-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-007)
  Galluzzo, Cecina, Naples, Volterra - Supply Tent, Enlisted Mens' Mess, Ward Tents, Post Office, USO performers, Generators, WACs and Nurses
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 121-140 1944 JULY-AUGUST, PHOTOS 19-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-008)
  Cecina, and Volterra; Laboratory, Refrigerators, Secretary of Navy Forrestal, Clinic, Dispensary, and Dental Clinic
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 141-160 1944 AUGUST-SEPTEMBER, PHOTOS 25-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-009)
  Cecina, Galluzzo, Castiglioncello, San Gimignano; General Giraud, Captain Wharton, General Clark, General Alexander, King George VI
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 161-180 1944 AUGUST-OCTOBER, PHOTOS 25-B&W 2/75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-010)
  San Gimignano, Galluzzo, Pietramala, Siena; Red Cross Workers, Laundry Tent, Offices, Congresswoman Mary Nourse Rogers
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 181-200 1944 NOVEMBER-1945 JANUARY, PHOTOS 21-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-011)
  Florence, and Pietremala; Winterization, Clare Booth Luce
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 201-220 1944 DECEMBER-1945 JANUARY, PHOTOS 33-B&W 2.75 X4.5 (Box-folder 06-012)
  Pietremala; Winterization, Wood Supply, Water Tower, Enlisted Mens' Quarters, Dental Clinic, Mess Hall, Ward Tents, Pre-Fabs
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 221-240 1944 AUGUST-1945 FEBRUARY, PHOTOS 23-B&W 2.75 X 4.5 (Box-folder 06-013)
  Pietremala, Cecina, and Florence; Secretary of War Stimson, Ward Tents
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 241-260 1945 FEBRUARY-MARCH, PHOTOS 30-B&W 2.75 X 4.5 (Box-folder 06-014)
  Pietramala, Florence, Pisa, Lucca, and Futa Pass
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 261-280 1944 AUGUST-1945 MAY, PHOTOS 19-B&W 2.75""X4.5"" (Box-folder 06-015)
  Pietramala, Buttapietra, Verona, Salo, and Carinola
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 281-300 1945 MARCH-MAY, PHOTOS 34-B&W 2.75 X 4.5 (Box-folder 06-016)
  1945 - Buttapietra, Pietramala, Verona, Mt. Beni, Venice; Ambulance Convoy, German Prison Camp Refugees, Chaplains' Tents, Red Cross Tent
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 301-320 1945 MAY, PHOTOS 19-B&W 2.75 X 4.5 (Box-folder 06-017)
  May, 1945 - Venice
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 321-340 1945 MAY, PHOTOS 16-B&W 2.75 X 4.5 (Box-folder 06-018)
  May 1945 - Venice, Buttapietra, Milan and Alassio
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 341-160 1945 MAY-JULY, PHOTOS 10-B&W 2.75 X 4.5 (Box-folder 06-019)
  Genoa, Lake Garda and Fasano
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 361-420 1945 JULY-SEPTEMBER, PHOTOS 9-B&W 2.75X4.5 (Box-folder 06-020)
  Fasano, Dezanzano, and Gardano
- VAN HANEY PHOTOS OF ITALY 421-450 1945 SEPTEMBER, PHOTO 10-B&W 2.75X4.5 (Box-folder 06-021)
  Po River, Gibraltar, and Dezanzano
- JOHN MCKOAN NOTEBOOK 1943 FEBRUARY, NOTEBOOK, RECORDS, CLIPPINGS, PHOTOS (Box-folder 07-000)
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 FEBRUARY, PHOTOS 2 B&W 3.75X5, 1 B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 08-001)
  1. Italian consulate building where McKoan took command Feb. 1943 2. Ward at 8th Evac. in Casablanca
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 MARCH, PHOTOS 2-B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 08-002)
  1. Ward tents, 8th EVAC. (on roof), Casablanca, Mar. 1943 2. 8th EVAC. at roof of Italian consulate, Casablanca
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 FEBRUARY- MARCH, PHOTOS 1-3.5 X 5 B&W, 1-3.25 X 4.5 B&W (Box-folder 08-003)
  1. Maj. Wintrop at work in dental clinic, Casablanca, Feb. 1943 2. Clean-up prior to move to Anfa Hill, March 1943
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 MARCH, PHOTOS 1-B&W 4X5, 1 B&W 3.25X4.5 (Box-folder 08-004)
  1. Tents 2. Enlisted men pack bags, March 1943
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 MAY, PHOTOS 1-B&W 3.25X4.5, 1-B&W 3.5X4.75 (Box-folder 08-005)
  1. View from Anfa Hill 2. Col. McKoan and driver at President Roosevelt's villa, Casablanca, May 1943
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA ND, PHOTOS 1-B&W 2.75X4.5, 1-B&W 3.25X2.75 (Box-folder 08-006)
  1. Capt. "Big" Kincopf, Asst. 2. Anfa Hotel, Casablanca, across street from 8th Evac.
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943, PHOTOS 1-B&W 3.5X4.25, 1-B&W 3.5X4.75 (Box-folder 08-007)
  1. Col. McKoan leaving for Anfa Hill 2. Enlisted men packing for Anfa Hill
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 MARCH, PHOTOS 2-'B&W 3.5X5.5 (Box-folder 08-008)
  1. Enlisted men cleaning area prior to move to Anfa Hill 2. 8th Evac. as it was set up on Anfa Hill, Casablanca, March 1943
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 MARCH 14, PHOTOS 2-B&W 3.5 X 5.5 (Box-folder 08-009)
  1. 8th Evac. 1st tents up at Anfa Hill, boxes contain ward supplies, X-ray equipment, etc. March 14, 1943 2. Ward tents being set up March 14, 1943
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA ND, PHOTOS 1-B&W 4 X 5, 1-B&W 3.25 X 4.5 (Box-folder 08-010)
  1. 8th Evac. Anfa Hill from Anfa Hotel 2. Col. McKoan awarding 1st Purple Hearts to wounded from 1st U.S. Infantry Division
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA ND, PHOTOS 1-B&W 4 X 5, 1- B&W 3.25 X 2.75 (Box-folder 08-011)
  1. General Wilson seated far left, 2nd Armd. Div. 2. Officers' tents, Anfa Hill
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 JUNE, PHOTOS 1-B&W 3.5 X 4.75, 1-B&W 3.25 X 4.5 (Box-folder 08-012)
  1. McKoan outside French Naval Headquarters, June 1943 2. McKoan with Dutch Consul Cabos, outside McKoan's tent on Anfa Hill, June 1943
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 JUNE, PHOTOS 2-B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 08-013)
  1. Funeral for PFC Harold C. Phillips who drowned 6/10/43 at Casablanca
  2. Funeral for Harold C. Phillips
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943, PHOTO 1-B&W 4X5 (Box-folder 08-014)
  Mechanics salvaging lumber in Casablanca from shipping crates
- 8TH EVAC. IN AFRICA 1943, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 X 5 (Box-folder 08-015)
  Arab children in North Africa
- 8TH EVAC. HOSPITAL IN AFRICA 1943 JULY 21, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 X 5.5 (Box-folder 08-016)
  Leaving Anfa Hill for Algiers: Loading trucks
- 8TH EVAC. IN AFRICA 1943, PHOTOS 2-B&W 3.25 X 4.5 (Box-folder 08-017)
  1. Algiers 2. Country scene en route to Algiers
- 8TH EVAC. IN AFRICA 1943 AUGUST, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 X 4.5 (Box-folder 08-018)
  Cathedral of the Black Virgin, Algiers
- 8TH EVAC. IN AFRICA 1943, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 X 3.75 (Box-folder 08-019)
  Col. Radke and John McKoan at Cap Matifou, Algiers
- 8TH EVAC. IN AFRICA 1943, PHOTOS 3-B&W 4 X 5 (Box-folder 08-020)
  Cap Matifou